[
  {
    "id": "802",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Security groups act like a firewall at the instance level whereas ___ are an additional layer of security that act at the subnet level?",
      "answers": [
        "Network ACLs",
        "DB Security Groups",
        "VPC Security Groups",
        "Route Tables"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Network ACLs"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "803",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "How many VPC's am I allowed in each AWS Region by default?",
      "answers": [
        "1",
        "2",
        "3",
        "4",
        "5",
        "10"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["5"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "804",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "VPC stands for?",
      "answers": [
        "Very Private Cloud",
        "Virtual Public Cloud",
        "Virtual Private Cloud",
        "Very Public Cloud"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Virtual Private Cloud"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "805",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "How many internet gateways can I attach to my custom VPC?",
      "answers": [
        "1",
        "2",
        "3",
        "4",
        "5",
        "10"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["1"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "806",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "You have a VPC with both public and private subnets. You have 3 EC2 instances that have been deployed in to the public subnet and each has internet access. You deploy a 4th instance using the same AMI and this instance does not have internet access. What could be the cause of this?",
      "answers": [
        "The instance needs a private route out to the internet.",
        "The instance needs either an Elastic IP address/Public IP address assigned to it.",
        "The instance's security group is preventing it from connecting to the internet.",
        "The ACL of the subnet is preventing access to the internet."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["The instance needs either an Elastic IP address/Public IP address assigned to it."]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "807",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "A VPC Flow Log allows you to do which?",
      "answers": [
        "capture information about the eip traffic going to and from network interfaces in your VPC",
        "capture information about the messages going to and from your applications in your EC2 instances in your VPC",
        "capture log information about your VPC",
        "capture log information about the EC2 instances in your VPC"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["capture information about the eip traffic going to and from network interfaces in your VPC"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "808",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "VPC Flow log data is stored _____?",
      "answers": [
        "using CloudWatch logs",
        "in S3",
        "using CloudTrail logs",
        "on the EC2 instance EBS volumes"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["using CloudWatch logs"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "809",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "After you've created a VPC Flow log, you can retrieve its data from the ________?",
      "answers": [
        "CloudWatch logs",
        "S3 bucket in which they're stored",
        "CloudTrail logs",
        "from the EC2 instance EBS volumes"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["CloudWatch logs"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "810",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 3",
      "question": "VPC Flow logs can be created at three levels?",
      "answers": [
        "VPC",
        "Subnet",
        "Network Interface level",
        "EC2 level"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["VPC",
        "Subnet",
        "Network Interface level"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "811",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 2",
      "question": "You can stream your VPC Flow logs to which of these?",
      "answers": [
        "Lambda functions",
        "ElasticSearch",
        "Kinesis",
        "Glue"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Lambda functions",
        "ElasticSearch"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "812",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "You can _________ from your VPC Flow logs streamed to Lambda or ElasticSearch?",
      "answers": [
        "programmatically react to log events",
        "store you log events",
        "build a data lake",
        "drive analytics"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["programmatically react to log events"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "813",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "You can _________ from your VPC Flow logs streamed to Lambda or ElasticSearch?",
      "answers": [
        "programmatically react to log events",
        "store you log events",
        "build a data lake",
        "drive analytics"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["programmatically react to log events"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "814",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "You can't enable flow logs for VPCs that are peered with your VPC unless the peer VPC _______?",
      "answers": [
        "is in your account",
        "is peered directly",
        "is in another account"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["is in your account"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "815",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "You can tag a VPC Flow Log?",
      "answers": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["false"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "816",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "After you've created a VPC Flow Log, you can change its configuration?",
      "answers": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["false"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "817",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "All ip traffic is monitored in a VPC Flow Log?",
      "answers": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["false"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "818",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "IP traffic generated by instances when they contact the Amazon DNS server is captured by your VPC Flow Log?",
      "answers": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["false"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "819",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "IP traffic generated by instances when they contact your own (created by you) DNS server is captured by your VPC Flow Log?",
      "answers": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["true"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "820",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "IP traffic generated by a Windows instance for an Amazon Windows license activation is captured by your VPC Flow Log?",
      "answers": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["false"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "821",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "IP traffic to and from 169.254.169.254 for instance meta data is captured by your VPC Flow Log?",
      "answers": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["false"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "822",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "DHCP traffic is captured by your VPC Flow Log?",
      "answers": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["false"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "823",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Traffic to the reserved ip address for the default VPC router is captured by your VPC Flow Log?",
      "answers": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["false"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "824",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "A NAT Instance is used to provide internet traffic to EC2 instances in ________?",
      "answers": [
        "private subnets",
        "public subnets",
        "NACLS",
        "Security Groups"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["private subnets"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "825",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "A NAT Instance is used to provide internet traffic to EC2 instances in a private subnet for things like __________?",
      "answers": [
        "downloading software updates (yum install ...)",
        "sending traffic to your database EC2 instance",
        "sending traffic to your application server EC2 instance",
        "sending traffic to your web server EC2 instance"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["downloading software updates (yum install ...)"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "826",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "A Bastion Host is used to ________ EC2 instances in private subnets?",
      "answers": [
        "securely administer (via SSH or RDP)",
        "allow outbound traffic from"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["securely administer (via SSH or RDP)"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "827",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 2",
      "question": "There are two different types of VPC endpoints?",
      "answers": [
        "Interface Endpoints",
        "Gateway Endpoints",
        "Public Endpoints",
        "Private Endpoints",
        "Bastion Endpoints"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Interface Endpoints",
        "Gateway Endpoints"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "828",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Interface VPC endpoints _______?",
      "answers": [
        "are an ENI attached to your EC2 instances which serves as a point of entry for traffic to your private subnet EC2 instances",
        "serve as a target for a route in your route table for traffic destined for your EC2 instances"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["are an ENI attached to your EC2 instances which serves as a point of entry for traffic to your private subnet EC2 instances"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "829",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Gateway VPC endpoints _______?",
      "answers": [
        "are an ENI attached to your EC2 instances which serves as a point of entry for traffic to your private subnet EC2 instances",
        "serve as a target for a route in your route table for traffic destined for your EC2 instances"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["serve as a target for a route in your route table for traffic destined for your EC2 instances"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "830",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Gateway VPC endpoints _______?",
      "answers": [
        "are an ENI attached to your EC2 instances which serves as a point of entry for traffic to your private subnet EC2 instances",
        "serve as a target for a route in your route table for traffic destined for your EC2 instances"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["serve as a target for a route in your route table for traffic destined for your EC2 instances"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "831",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "When creating a NAT Instance, you need to ______?",
      "answers": [
        "disable the Source/Destination check on the instance",
        "assign a DNS name to the NAT Instance",
        "assign an ip address to the NAT Instance"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["disable the Source/Destination check on the instance"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "832",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "With a NAT Instance, you need to ______?",
      "answers": [
        "place the NAT Instance in a public subnet",
        "place the NAT Instance in a private subnet",
        "assign an ip address to the NAT Instance"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["place the NAT Instance in a public subnet"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "833",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "With a NAT Instance, there must be a route out of the private subnet to the NAT Instance?",
      "answers": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["true"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "834",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "If you are experiencing bottlenecking with your NAT Instance, ________?",
      "answers": [
        "increase the size of the NAT Instance",
        "add more EBS volumes to the NAT Instance",
        "switch the NAT Instance to a Bastion Host"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["increase the size of the NAT Instance"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "835",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 3",
      "question": "To make your NAT Instance highly available you can do which?",
      "answers": [
        "use Auto-scaling Groups",
        "use multiple subnets in different AZs",
        "write a fail-over script",
        "use an Application ELB"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["use Auto-scaling Groups",
        "use multiple subnets in different AZs",
        "write a fail-over script"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "836",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "NAT Instances are _________?",
      "answers": [
        "behind a Security Group",
        "behind a NACL",
        "behind a Bastion Host",
        "behind a Network Gateway"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["behind a Security Group"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "837",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Which is the preferred solution these days?",
      "answers": [
        "NAT Instance",
        "NAT Gateway"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["NAT Gateway"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "838",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "NAT Gateways scale __________?",
      "answers": [
        "Automatically",
        "Incrementally",
        "through configuration"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Automatically"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "839",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "NAT Gateways are associated with Security Groups?",
      "answers": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["false"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "840",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "NAT Gateways are automatically assigned a _________?",
      "answers": [
        "public ip address",
        "private ip address",
        "DNS name",
        "route table entry"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["public ip address"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "841",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "After you create a NAT Gateway you need to _________?",
      "answers": [
        "update your route table entries",
        "remove your route tables",
        "associate it with an EC2 instance",
        "associate it with a Security Group"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["update your route table entries"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "842",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "VPC",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Which is more secure?",
      "answers": [
        "NAT Instance",
        "NAT Gateway"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["NAT Gateway"]
    }
  }
]
